{ 
  
    "elements" :[ 
    {
      "question" : "The atomic number of an atom is the number of ______ in the atom's nucleus.",
      "answers" : {
        "a": "Electrons",
        "b": "Neutrons",
        "c": "Protons"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "The rows in Periodic Table are called __________.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Periods",
        "b": "Classes",
        "c": "Chemicals",
        "d": "Blocks"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question" : "Which one of the following elements is very rare?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "Thorium",
        "b" : "Uranium",
        "c" : "Francium",
        "d" : "Nihonium"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "c"
    },
    {
      "question" : "How many periods and groups are present in the periodic table?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "7 periods and 18 groups",
        "b" : "8 periods and 7 groups",
        "c" : "7 periods and 7 groups",
        "d" : "8 periods and 8 groups"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following forms the basis of the modern periodic table?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "Atomic Number",
        "b" : "Atomic Mass",
        "c" : "Number of Nucleons",
        "d" : "All of these"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "a"
    },
    {
      "question" : "What happens to the electropositive character of elements on moving from left to right in a periodic table?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "Increases",
        "b" : "Decreases",
        "c" : "First increases then decreases",
        "d" : "First decreases then increases"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "b"
    },
    {
      "question" : "What is the other name for group 18th elements?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "Noble Gases",
        "b" : "Alkali Metals",
        "c" : "Alkaline earth metals",
        "d" : "Halogens"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question" : "Which of the following elements has 2 shells and both are completely filled?",
      "answers": {
        "a" : "Helium",
        "b" : "Neon",
        "c" : "Calcium",
        "d" : "Boron"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "b"
    },
    {
      "question" : "Which of the following statements are TRUE?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "The first 94 elements in Periodic Table occur naturally",
        "b" : "Elements 95 to 118 have only been synthesized in laboratories or nuclear reactors",
        "c" : "Alkali Metals occupy the left-most column of the Periodic Table",
        "d" : "All are True"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "d"
    },
    {
      "question" : "Who proposed Law of Triads?",
      "answers" : {
        "a" : "Dobereiner",
        "b" : "John Newlands",
        "c" : "Lothan Grenger",
        "d" : "Michal Philip Gardener"
      },
      "correctAnswer" : "a"
    }
    ]
}
